<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Sys on vBlog</title>
    <link>/tags/sys/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sys on vBlog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2020 Vlad Vasiliu</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 09:22:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/tags/sys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv6 prefix delegation on FreeBSD router</title>
      <link>/post/20180827-0922-ipv6_prefix_delegation_freebsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 09:22:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20180827-0922-ipv6_prefix_delegation_freebsd/</guid>
      <description>Goal I&amp;rsquo;m attempting to set up a router box in to replace my SFR router on a home network. As my SFR plan has native IPv6, this box will request a prefix delegation and set up IPv6 routing for the computers on the home network. It will also handle NAT for IPv4.
This is supposed to be a drop-in replacement for the SFR provided box, so it will have to:</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Chrome in dual screen kiosk mode on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>/post/20180807-1626-dual_screen_kiosk_ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 16:27:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20180807-1626-dual_screen_kiosk_ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Background At work we have to large TV screens used for displaying Grafana dashboards. They are both connected to the same PC.
The PC was running Windows so anytime the PC would reboot, we would have to manually conenct to it via VNC and move the browsers around and set them in full screen mode.
As we are in the office only during work hours, the PC would be shut down and restarted everyday.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Python in SaltStack reactor</title>
      <link>/post/20161231-1210-using_python_in_saltstack_reactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 12:11:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/20161231-1210-using_python_in_saltstack_reactor/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you need to do some complex actions in a Salt Reactor in which case Python comes in handy.
The documentation is not very clear on how to write Python states. The main point is that Salt expects a structure that can be compiled to a Python dictionary. The run() function has to return a dictionary which resembles the state you would write with YAML.
Here&amp;rsquo;s an example to add a domain to route 53:</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
